# Piyush Biswal

#### Senior Full Stack Developer

A FullStack Developer with more than 5 years of experience with Fortune 500 and startup companies and having an In-depth understanding of web technologies. Involved in design, planning, and implementation of various scalable Web & Mobile applications using open source technologies. An Innovation Catalyst- Tech Aficionado



≥ piyush.rvk@gmail.com

+918792151911



piyush-repo.github.io



S live:piyushbiswal

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Software Engineer (Jul 2018 - Present) Eze Software India Pvt Ltd.

An US based Fin-tech Investment Management Suite Product Development company, specially nurturing products for Buy and Sell Side with 1800+ clients

- Working as a FullStack Developer for the Commissions Product, driving it from end to end along with CI/CD pipelines.
- Developed an important feature which led to the on boarding of multiple clients and brought revenues to the company.
- Added value to the development process and delivery by working on cross team products with latest Coding standards.
- Running business analysis meetings, gathering requirements and designing solutions along with the team.
- Prepare estimates for new projects and work with the Product Manager on planning of new features and enhancements.
- Building user stories and Delivering solutions in Agile Scrum.
- Collaborated with QA's for testing of user stories.

#### Senior Software Engineer (June 2018 - May 2018) Mobinius Technology

ChatBot, Web and Mobile App development

- Worked as a Node JS Backend Developer along with the team for development of apps which includes a Contract management system, Minicampus (An EdTech platform), Timesheet management and Qart (An Ecommerce IOS Mobile App).
- Implemented Job Schedulers for automation Data Sync and triggering alerts .
- Built an ecommerce web app to sell products online. Increased company sales by
- Built a timesheet and leave application web app to bug down manual process and give a holistic view of workforce across departments.
- Worked for API documentation for QA Client reference.
- Worked on load testing of Rest API endpoints .
- Implemented JWT token based authentication and session management for API's .
- Took active role for deployment of apps into Production, Staging and Testing Environments.
- RA and documentation from Clients and PR reviews.
- POC on Chat Bots using Google Dialog Flow.

# SVC Info Developer (March 2014 - June 2017)

#### Hewlett Packard Enterprise

**Enterprise Product & Solution** 

- Developed an Intuitive Dashboard for displaying the Real Time Key Metrics like Change management for an Telecom Giant.
- Worked in a Data warehousing Project and developed Reports focused on seeing KPI's with near real time statistics
- Implemented Map view to locate the Site hubs with live status using Google Map APIs.
- Built an Scalable application to be used by 1Million+ users.
- Worked with stakeholders for timely demos and delivery of the product with optimum client satisfaction
- Created PLSql Packages, procedures and scheduled Jobs for ETL process.
- Involved in the UAT of the Dashboard.

# **SKILLS**



# **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

Node Project Scaffolding 🗹

Translator With IBM Watson 🗹

# **EDUCATION**

BE In Electronics & Telecom(2009-13) BPUT - CGPA - 8.5 /10

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

Organization Name

# INTERESTS

